# **Daniel Lew**

## **Profile**

I'm a Software Engineer based in Toronto, Canada. I'm a co-creator of Stagehand ☑, a drop-in review apps service for frontend applications. I have multiple years of experience with both the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems. I am also comfortable with cloud services such as AWS.

## Skills

**Backend** Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL,

MongoDB, RESTful APIs

**Frontend** 

JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, JQuery

**Tooling** 

Git, Linux, Pivotal Tracker

Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku

## **Professional Experience**

## **Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand**

2020 - present

- Co-created Stagehand, an open-source review apps service for frontend applications
- Prototyped and built Stagehand's infrastructure by stitching together AWS and GitHub Actions
- Utilized GitHub Actions to automatically set up and tear down review apps in response to events
- Designed cloud infrastructure on AWS to host frontend review apps
- Implemented review apps wrapper to provide customizable dashboard using Service Workers and clientside code
- Built an intuitive CLI for the user-interface and collaboration across multiple devices
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study: https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑
- Collaborated daily with a fully remote team of engineers

## Full-stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2018 - present

- A Trello-like collaboration board built with Rails and React/Redux
- A multi room chat app over websockets hosted on a VPS, built with Node.js/React
- A Request Bin-like tool to receive and inspect request payloads, built with Express JS, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL. Set up on a VPS
- A Rails API to manage projects, users, and auth, with an RSpec test suite
- A water scheduler to keep track of your plants, built with Ruby and Sinatra

## Event Manager, Oliver & Bonacini

2015 - 2020 | Toronto, Canada

Managing massive, high-end events such as TIFF, Human Rights Watch, Wedluxe

## **Education**

**Launch School** 2018 - 2020

Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum, mastery-based learning Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, HTTP, HTML, CSS | launchschool.com/employers ☑

Marketing Management, Humber College

2015 - 2016 | Toronto, Canada

Psychology and Sexuality, Marriage, and Family Studies, University of Waterloo

2008 – 2013 | Waterloo, Canada